RESUME

CLIFFORD NELSON

DESIGN TECHNOLOGIST / PROTOTYPER

Culver City, California 90232

E: cliffordRyanNelson@gmail.com || T: 510-424-1101 || clifford.codes

Hi there. I'm Clifford.

My entire career has focused on digital media, from Broadcast Stations on board Navy Ships, to Digital TV and Web User Interfaces: I've had a wide range of experiences in the industry.

My enthusiasm has always been human computer interaction, products can be well engineered but successful products will be led by design. With my background in engineering and an education in Psychology and Design I bring this unique perspective to the table that blends engineering and design in harmony.

As a design technologist I've found value in delivering design concepts as prototypes. Prototypes that are true to design intent such as user flows and design-system but lack the further engineering efforts that are required for the many app environments. This also helps with trying and scraping ideas rapidly - prototypes can be spun up quickly to test an idea that may or may not need further exploration.

My ideal role will be one that bridges the gap between design and development, working closely with all stakeholders including: design, engineering, and other key business stakeholders. While also staying active in the industry by leveraging and learning new technologies as they emerge.

Best.

Clifford Nelson

RESUME

CLIFFORD NELSON

DESIGN TECHNOLOGIST / PROTOTYPER

Culver City, California 90232

E: cliffordRyanNelson@gmail.com || T: 510-424-1101 || clifford.codes

Experience

FULL STACK DESIGN

WARNER BROS. DISCOVERY, 2021-PRESENT

Supporting the HBO Max growth marketing department in driving the visual and technical success for the creative and visual execution of WarnerMedia's digital and online marketing channels. Focused on coding and creating at the same time, with the latest innovations in technology with HTML, CSS and beyond.

FROND-END DEVELOPER

INTUIT TURBOTAX, 2020-2021

While working with Intuit, again, I worked with some familiar faces while helping to improve and build new, reusable web components. Closely collaborating with many stakeholders: including Design, SEO, Marketing, and others, to design and build delightful and engaging experiences for production and A/B testing. Utilizing relatively modern technologies such as Handlebars for templating and Scalable CSS for styling to deliver to typical dotCom and AMP pages.

DESIGN PROTOTYPER

NETFLIX [FIRST PROFESSIONAL SERVICES], 2019–2020

To support the growth marketing team at Netflix I was asked to help build prototypes of sign-up experiences both in-app and via 3rd party flows. Utilizing web technologies like React and GSAP we created web-apps meant for a TV - often referred to as a "10 foot device" because the user is typically about 10 feet away. This method allows us to create hi-fidelity prototypes to simulate these environments for user testing, research and design feasibility. I also worked briefly with the Core Design team to help with the internal Design System, and also worked briefly with the Studio Design team on 2 internal apps.

CREATIVE TECHNOLOGIST / PROTOTYPER

GOOGLE [SYNERGIG CREATIVE], 2018–2019

Contributed to the exploration of Doodle X, or what is the future of the Google Doodle and how might Google become more human-like and trustworthy. Using web technologies like Angular, Material, and GSAP I recreated the Google ecosphere to demonstrate radical ideas in an effort to spead the Doodle to more Google surfaces. In this role I worked closely with the Doodle designers to explore posibilities and worked briefly with the

Education

PLATT COLLEGE SAN DIEGO, 2011-2014

BACHELORS OF SCIENCE, WEB DESIGN GPA: 4.0, CLASS VALEDICTORIAN

Relevant Coursework:

- Fundamentals of Web Design
- Web Campaign Implementation
- Design for Usability
- · Responsive Web Design
- Programming for Designers
- Scripting for the Web
- Content Management Systems

Skills

- UI/UX Prototyping
- Web Design/Development
- Responsive Web Design
- HTML5/CSS3
- JavaScript & JSON
- Web Animations
- GSAP, Lottie
- Box2D, Canvas
- React, Angular
- Material
- Open Props, Bootstrap
- GitHub
- Adobe Creative Suite
- CLI
 - * a few key words that highlight my skills, in no particular order

DESIGN TECHNOLOGIST / PROTOTYPER

Culver City, California 90232
E: cliffordRyanNelson@gmail.com || T: 510-424-1101 || clifford.codes

Engineering team to communicate design intent effectively.

DESIGN ENGINEER

UBER [TEKSYSTEMS], 2017-2018

Collaborate closely with Design team to deliver engaging experiences using the latest in front-end technologies like React. Responsible for customer faceing efforts such as the blog, about and FAQ pags. Design and build internal tools to make tedious and/or difficult tasks easy and efficient for non-technical content providers.

Environment: HTML/SCSS/JS/React

Build internal tools to aid marketing efforts

Integrate with Contentful CMS

SENIOR CREATIVE DEVELOPER

AKQA, 2017-2017

Working as a resource in Marketing and Communications for tech company in Sunnyvale/Cupertino. Developing direct mailers and .com experiences, based on design compositions. Pixel perfect rendering of experiences from design to delivery is key. Rapid turn around times.

Environment: HTML/SCSS/Handlebars

Developing direct mailers and .com experiences Contribute to internal development tools

EXPERIENCE DESIGN PROTOTYPER

INTUIT TURBOTAX [INTEGRATED ASSOCIATES], 2016-2017

Experience Design (XD) Prototyping is the synthesis of design and development. In this role I'd partner with researchers, product managers and other designers to define and deliver new features, test new concepts and assist with final implementation. Details are critical as we'd iterate on complex interactions, animations and pixel-perfect visual designs.

Environment: HTML/LESS/JavaScript/PHP/AngularJS

Explore new product concepts through delivery prototypes using the latest in front-end technologies including AngularJS, Google Material, and GSAP

Engage with customers and learn quickly through iterative prototyping Advise, collaborate with, and synthesize feedback from designers and researchers

Fulfill several project requests simultaneously while meeting tight deadlines

Work with front-end engineers to ensure delivery of intended design

DESIGN TECHNOLOGIST / PROTOTYPER

Culver City, California 90232
E: cliffordRyanNelson@gmail.com || T: 510-424-1101 || clifford.codes

FRONT-END SOFTWARE ENGINEER

INTUIT TURBOTAX [INTEGRATED ASSOCIATES], 2015-2016

Responsible for delivering engaging responsive marketing content to help our customers understand the offerings and choose the right product for them through landing pages, product up-sells, A/B tests, via a wide range of front-end technologies.

Environment: HTML/LESS/JavaScript/Handlebars
Convert wire-frames and mock-ups into prototype pages and applications.
Partner effectively with all team members to deliver against
commitments
Contribute to early quality activities, including peer reviews of
estimates, designs and code
Resolve defects/bugs during QA testing, pre-production, production, and
post-release patches
Agile Development, SCRUM, and Extreme Programming methodologies like
MOB Programming

UI/UX SOFTWARE ENGINEER

IBM [EXPERIS IT], 2014-2015

Responsible for designing and implementing user interactions and the interface for the Military logistics platforms: Army BCS3 & Navy One-touch. Partner with client stakeholders to define and deliver critical features for equipment procurement and tracking. I was brought into this role to help with usability and design of already established solutions. Manipulated Java to define style classes of web elements and created those classes in a LESS pre-processor.

Environment: HTML/LESS/JavaScript/Java
User Interface / User Experience Design & Development
Build reusable code and libraries
Provide feedback about the technical feasibility and usability
Collaborate with other team members and stakeholders

INTERACTION DESIGNER

MOR FURNITURE FOR LESS, 2014-2014

Responsibilities in this role include partnering with stakeholders to reimagine and create new experiences for customer information gathering and employee education/training. In the several weeks in this role I delivered an internal Multi-Installation of WordPress CMS that severed as the foundation for MOR Xpress, an employee education platform & new concepts for customer credit approval processing that removed the burden of filing out multiple forms from the customer.

Environment: HTML/LESS/JavaScript/PHP/WordPress User Interface / User Experience Design & Development WordPress CMS, custom template Integration with established LDAP Wire-framing and interaction design

DESIGN TECHNOLOGIST / PROTOTYPER

Culver City, California 90232

E: cliffordRyanNelson@qmail.com || T: 510-424-1101 || clifford.codes

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

GASLAMP MEDIA, 2014-2014

Responsibilities include developing design compositions into production ready templates using CMS technologies such as WordPress and Drupal. As a side project I Designed & Developed a WordPress Plug-in that would calculate price of herbs from small amounts to bulk pricing.

Environment: HTML/LESS/JavaScript/PHP/WordPress Develop websites in a CMS, WordPress & Drupal, production environment. Utilizing web technologies, frameworks and skeleton themes to quickly produce unique CMS themes.

Collaborate directly with clients, via phone and in person working sessions.

UI/UX design mocks to prototypes and working products Design and implement new features and tools Optimize web applications to maximize speed and scale for clients

INTERACTION DESIGNER

CMS CODE, INC, 2013-2014

Utilize several CMS technologies to deliver web registration products to fundraising clients. Responsibilities include working directly with clients to define and deliver registration forms, donation forms, and web/marketing presence. Also served as Interaction Designer and Prototyper for company development project. Most notable accomplishment was taking an existing static donation form template and adding responsiveness to fit any size screen from small mobile to large desktop.

Environment: HTML/LESS/JavaScript/PHP/WordPress/BlackBaudCMS Work directly with clients, via phone and in person working sessions Writing and editing content Determining technical requirements Designing new web-page layouts Updating existing websites and web forms by adding responsive web design techniques Manage Source Control

TEACHING ASSISTANT

PLATT COLLEGE, 2013-2014

While attending Platt College full-time, in my Junior/Senior years, I also served as a Teachers Assistant in the lower level and upper level classes. Responsibilities include helping students with design and technical advise in the Adobe Creative Suite and Front-End Technologies.

Assist teachers in class size of more than 10 students Provide technical and design advice to students utilizing the Adobe Creative Suite and Front-End Technologies Maintain classroom functionality Take detailed attendance reports Tutor students after class hours

RESUME

CLIFFORD NELSON

DESIGN TECHNOLOGIST / PROTOTYPER

Culver City, California 90232

 $\textbf{E} : \ \texttt{cliffordRyanNelson@gmail.com} \ \ || \ \ \textbf{T} : \ 510\text{-}424\text{-}1101 \ \ || \ \ \texttt{clifford.codes}$

DESIGN TECHNOLOGIST / PROTOTYPER

Culver City, California 90232

E: cliffordRyanNelson@qmail.com || T: 510-424-1101 || clifford.codes

B&L BIKE AND SPORT

SALES ASSOCIATE / BICYCLE MECHANIC, 2012-2013

It had always been a dream of mine to work in a bike shop, so when I went back to school I sought out a part-time bike shop job and landed a spot at this company.

Act as personal shopper for high-end Specialized brand bicycles Excellent use of interpersonal skills
Operate point of sale system
Maintain and repair customer bicycles and rental bicycle fleet

OMNITEC SOLUTIONS INC

BROADCAST FNGINFFR, 2006-2012

After an enlistment in the Active Duty Navy I landed a job with the Civilian Sector Navy as a Government Contractor. This position was similar to my role while on active duty but focus on one specific piece of equipment - SITE TV.

Provided technical support for the Navy's Television Broadcast Systems including: "SITE TV"-Broadcast Studios, "21DSS", "TV-DTS" & "AFRTS" Satellite Television Systems, "CKT27" RF Distribution Systems & Shipboard Surveillance Systems.

Technical Support including: System Maintenance, Operator Training, Engineering Documentation,

Technical Support including: System Maintenance, Operator Training, Engineering Documentation, Engineering Change Orders, System Troubleshooting, etc.

Lead Engineer in the Design/Build of the Next Generation of Site TV 400 Broadcast Studio with networked Video on Demand capabilities. Including Research & Development, User Interface Design, Technical Documentation New Product Design & Procurement

User Interface Label Design including Operating & Maintaining Epilog Laser Engraver Active Security Clearance

LIGHTWORKS ARCHITECTURAL LIGHTING

AUDIO/VIDEO HOME SYSTEMS EXPERT, 2006-2006

As a home systems installation technician I was responsible for wiring entire homes with low-voltage communication wiring, head-end rack system design and build, and programming of state of the art communication and entertainment equipment.

Complete pre-wire and installation of advanced audio/video communication equipment in high-end residential and commercial properties

Design & build head-end equipment racks for centralized A/V & home automation systems Elan home systems technician - Installation and programming training course

UNITED STATES NAVY

INTERIOR COMMUNICATIONS ELECTRICIAN, 2002–2006

After high-school and vocational school I joined the Navy during the Bush administration when we first sent troops to Iraq.

 ${\tt Maintain,\ Troubleshoot\ \&\ Repair\ shipboard\ equipment\ including\ Televisions,\ Telephones,\ and\ Alarm\ Systems.}$

System repair parts procurement and inventory Head Gyro-Compass Technician

Security Clearance